Memorabilia Collection, 1782-2011 (bulk 1866-1997): Finding Aid AC053
University Archives
- Series 14: Smoking Accessories, 1870-1973; 18 boxes
  - Class day clay pipe with ribbon, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
    Class day pipe. With orange and black ribbon, blue painted bowl.
  - Corn cob pipe, 1897; 1 item (Box 73)
    Class of 1897. Long bowl.
  - Corn cob pipe, 1888; 1 item (Box 73)
    Class of 1888.
  - Corn cob pipe, 1878; 1 item (Box 73)
    Class of 1878.
  - Corn cob pipe, 1878; 1 item (Box 73)
    Class of 1878. Painted orange.
  - Corncob pipe bowl with "79", undated; 1 item (Box 73)
    Corncob with "79."
  - Wooden pipe, 1923; 1 item (Box 73)
    "P '23"
  - Wooden pipe "Spencer '70", 1870; 1 item (Box 73)
    "Spencer '70" Signatures of other members of 1870 class. Stem separated from bowl.
    Ex4533; gift of JC Spencer '07.
  - Wooden pipe bowl "Thalna '06", 1906; 1 item (Box 73)
    "Thalna '06"
    EX5010; Kienbusch. Gift.
  - Clay pipe, 1891; 1 item (Box 73)
    Class of 1891.
  - Clay pipe, 1881; 1 item (Box 73)
    Class of 1881.
  - Pittsburgh Club matchbook, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
    "HYP" H-Y-P Club of Pittsburgh.
  - Class of 1932 35th reunion matchbook, 1967; 1 item (Box 73)
    "32's 35th" White book with tiger.
  - Princeton Ribbon from cigarettes, circa 1891-1900; 1 item (Box 73)
    Cigarette purchase souvenir. Orange ribbon with pennant. "Twelfth night cigarettes".
    AR.1992.053
  - Class Day Pipe, 1898; 1 item (Box 76)
    1898 white ceramic with bamboo stem.
  - Clay pipe, bamboo shaft, 1899; 1 item (Box 76)
    Class of 1899. Bamboo shaft.
  - Clay pipe, bamboo shaft, 1897; 1 item (Box 76)
    Class of 1897. Bamboo shaft.
  - Clay pipe, bamboo shaft, 1899; 1 item (Box 76)
    1899. Bamboo shaft, painted with shield.
    AR2000.052
  - Clay pipe, 1889; 1 item (Box 77)
    Class of 1889.
  - Clay pipe, 1892; 1 item (Box 77)
    Class of 1892.
  - Clay pipe, "41-91", circa 1891; 1 item (Box 77)
    "41-91". Painted orange and black.
  - Clay pipe, 1890; 1 item (Box 77)
    1890. Painted orange and black.
  - Clay pipe, 1887; 1 item (Box 77)
    1887. Painted orange.
  - Clay pipe, 1888; 1 item (Box 77)
    1888
  - White clay pipe, undated; 1 item (Box 77)
  - Palmer Stadium pipe holder, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
    Shaped like Palmer Stadium. Metal.
  - Ashtray, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
    Round with university seal. Green ceramic.
  - Ashtray with tiger and "54", undated; 1 item (Box 78)
    White ceramic with tiger, "54."
    AR.1996.043
  - Triangle Show ashtray, 1954; 1 item (Box 78)
    Glass, "Princeton Triangle Show 1/2/54 'Malice in Wonderland' 60th anniversary."
  - Class of 1904 45th Reunion ashtray, 1949; 1 item (Box 78)
    Class of 1904 45th Reunion 1949. Round, orange.
  - Ashtray, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
    University seal. Rectangular, white and green-brown.
  - Ashtray, Pebble Beach, 1966; 1 item (Box 78)
    Pebble Beach 1966. "See you in the West". White, round.
  - Nassau Hall wedgwood ashtray, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
    Nassau Hall. Wedgwood, white.
  - Class of 1916 45th Reunion cigarette pack, 1961; 1 item (Box 78)
    Reunions. 1916's 45th. Orange.
    AR.1998.020
  - Class of 1896 gold cigarette case, circa 1928; 1 item (Box 78)
    Cover inscribed with initials "EBH;" inscription reads: "To Edward Blanchard Hodge from the Class of 1896"
    AR.2003.059
  - Class of 1916 45th Reunion cigarette pack, 1961; 1 item (Box 78)
  - Class of 1916 40th Reunion cigarette pack, 1956; 1 item (Box 78)
    Reunions. 1916's 40th. Orange.
  - Hobey Baker silver and gold cigarette case, 1914 September 15; 1 item (Box 78)
    Inscription "H.A.H.B. from P.R.P. 2nd September 15, 1914." Given to Hobey Baker by Percy R. Pyne.
  - Class of 1923 50th reunion ashtray, 1973; 1 item (Box 78)
    Reunions. Class of 1923 50th. White with gold edge, with shield and tiger.
  - Pewter and china ashtray, undated; 1 item (Box 78)
    "Princeton" and shield. Pewter and china.
  - Cannon-shaped metal ashtray, 1879; 1 item (Box 79)
    1879. Black cannon shape. Metal.
  - Ashtray with university seal, undated; 1 item (Box 79)
    University seal. Rectangular, orange with cigarette stand.
    EX5007
  - Class of 1877 25th reunion ashtray with tiger, 1902; 1 item (Box 79)
    Class of 1877, 25th. Black with tiger.
  - Class of 1877 55th reunion ashtray, 1932; 1 item (Box 79)
    Class of 1877, 55th Reunion. Black with U seal.
  - Class of 1904 3rd reunion cigarette case, 1907; 1 item (Box 79)
    "Triennial 04 Reunion". Empty case of reunion cigarettes.
  - Cigarette case, undated; 1 item (Box 79)
    Black. Seal on front.
    Given by William E. Curtis '29.
  - Cigarette pack, undated; 1 item (Box 79)
    "Princeton". Red and white design.
  - Leather cigarette case in honor of W. Wilson, 1913 March 3; 1 item (Box 79)
    "Reception and Smoker in Honor of W. Wilson, 1913" Tan with U seal. Given by Princeton Alumni Association of District of Columbia, March 3, 1913.
    EX4578; Gift of Laurence C. Woods, Class of 1922.
  - Classical Seminary metal ashtray, undated; 1 item (Box 80)
    Classical Seminary Princeton University. Metal.
  - Class of 1894 45th reunion ashtray, 1939; 1 item (Box 80)
    Forty fifth '94 Reunion. Black, round.
  - Heermance's Silver Cigarette Box, 1950; 1 item (Box 80)
    Gift to Radcliffe Heermance, Director of Admission 1909-1950.
    AR.2002.007
  - Tobacco urn, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
    Pipes and U seal design. Metal.
    AR1995.062
  - Tobacco sign: Tiger chewing tobacco, undated; 1 item (Box 93)
    "Tiger chewing tobacco,"orange and black. 2' x 1.5'
  - Silver tiger lighter, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
    Silver lighter with picture of tiger that belonged to Henry Welsh Rogers, Class of 1896.
    AR.2006.044
  - Clay pipe, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
    White clay pipe
    AR.2007.004
  - Pouch with pipe and matches, undated; 1 item (Box 73)
    Class of 1911. Brown pouch with Princeton Shield and orange and black ribbon with pin attached. Broken pipe and matches inside.
  - Silver ashtray, undated; 1 item (Box 79)
    Silver ashtray with "P" in the middle and "Princeton University" around the edges.
    AR.2004.059